Seidenberg, Jacob Additional Arbitration Files 5988
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
1950-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5988
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3126442
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 22, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 24, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files B 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records
Arbitration, Industrial--United States--Sources.; Seidenberg, Jacob.
3126442
- Aberdeen Proving Ground, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  11/3/93 - 2/8/94. Termination of employment.
- American Federation of Government Employees, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  2/18/88- 1/6/89. Job classification.
- Armstrong World Industries, Inc., 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  3/28/89 -3/9/90. Seniority, this was a cancelled case.
- Baltimore County Public Schools, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1/19/94 -2/25/94. School's & college's; workload, transfer. Teacher's position on unresolved issues presented to fact finding panel, in a folder.
- Baltimore Sun Mailers Union #88, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  2/16/88 -12/31/89. Contract interpretation.
- Birmingham Southern Railroad Co., 1975-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  4/22/75 -4/20/89. Rates of pay, overtime, lunch period, premium pay.
- Charles County Board of Education, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  7/31/92 -10/14/92. Assignment of jobs, workload, workweek, rates of pay, incentive pay, sick leave, leaves of absence.
- Chicago & Northwestern Transportation Co., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  9/18/91 - 12/14/91. Vacancy, assignment of jobs, premium pay. Some related cases from other companies.
- CSX Transportation, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  12/5/91 - 1/14/93. Crew size.
- CSX Transportation, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  1/21/79 - 8/11/92. Assignment of jobs.
- CSX Transportation, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  11/28/79. Compensation, discipline.
- CSX Transportation (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Reinstatement, seniority, compensation. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  12/17/92. Discipline. Transcripts.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  1/94. Reinstatement, termination of employment, compensation. Transcripts & agreements.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  7/28/94- 11/21/94. Premium pay, assignment of jobs, rates of pay.
- CSX Transportation (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Assignment of jobs, premium pay.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  5/94. Rates of pay, premium pay. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  6/94. Assignment of jobs, rates of pay. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  6/94. Premium pay, assignment of jobs. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  11/30/90 - 5/31/91. Assignment of jobs.
- CSX Transportation, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  3/6/92-5/2/94. Assignment of jobs, contract interpretation.
- CSX Transportation, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  6/20/86- 11/14/87. Assignment of jobs, contract interpretation, seniority. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  5/94 - 6/94. Assignment of jobs, rates of pay, premium pay, call-in. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  1/94. Seniority, reinstatement, compensation. Exhibits.
- CSX Transportation, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  4/92 - 5/26/92. Contract interpretation, assignment of jobs.
- CSX Transportation, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  4/25/92- 1/14/94. Contract interpretation, job classification, assignment of jobs. Exhibits.
- Civil Rights Commission (Box 2, Folder 6)
  News from U.S. Department of Labor.
- District of Columbia Doctors Council, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  6/28/91 - 8/14/92. Discrimination.
- Eastern Air Lines, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  9/30/87 - 10/28/88. Termination of employment.
- Eastern Air Lines, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  5/13/87 - 12/17/88. Termination of employment, supervisory employees.
- Eastern Air Lines, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Agreement with Air Line Pilots Association International. Not in a folder.
- Emergency Board, 1950-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  11/2/50-7/2/74. Reports, also see box #9.
- Exxon Co., U.S.A., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  6/28/88 - 12/29/88. Termination of employment.
- Giant Food, Inc., 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  6/25/93. Termination of employment.
- Giant Food, Inc., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  1/31/89 - 8/4/89. Termination of employment.
- H.S. Crocker Co., Inc., 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  8/2/91 - 3/2/92. Severance pay, shutdown, contract interpretation.
- Health Care Financing Administration, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  10/24/88- 11/4/88. Assignment of jobs, promotion, back pay, contract interpretation.
- Holly Farms, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  10/25/88-1/11/89. Termination of employment.
- Independent Distributors, Inc., 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  11/1/88 -1/17/89. Arbitration procedure, grievance procedure.
- Kroger Bakery, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  11/30/81-4/26/82. Posting.
- Locke Insulators, Inc., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  1/12/94 - 3/10/94. Premium pay.
- Maryland State Teachers Association, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8A)
  5/10/93 - 1/3/94. Suspension. Handbook, agreement.
- Metropolitan Police Department (in D.C.), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  10/10/88-4/6/89. Termination of employment, arbitrability.
- Montgomery County Education Association (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Fact finding exhibits. Round two.
- Montgomery County Education Association. (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  Articles open prior to mediation. Workload, salaries, fringe benefits.
- Montgomery County Education Association, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  6/24/91 -9/28/93. Agreement re-negotiated and ratified. Correspondence.
- National Academy of Arbitrators (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Formal advisory opinions, constitution and by-laws, code of professional responsibility for arbitrators of Labor - Management disputes.
- Pennfield Farms, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  2/25/93 - 10/15/93. Arbitrability, union security, seniority, termination of employment.
- Resorts International, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  6/28/88 - 4/13/89. Discipline, termination of employment, back pay-
- SES, Staff Development Work Group, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  6/9/92. Memorandum about system wide training unit, school improvement training unit.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  9/23/92 - 2/9/93. Premium pay, rates of pay.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  4/22/91 - 6/7/91. Correspondence.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  11/1/94. Formal investigation and correspondence, transcripts of investigation.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  4/18/93 - 3/8/94. Transcript of testimony taken in formal investigation.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  10/6/92 - 10/4/94. Compensation, termination of employment, suspension. Formal investigation transcripts.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  6/2/94 - 2/2/95. Compensation, suspension. Transcripts from formal investigation.
- Southern Pacific Lines, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 2A)
  7/10/91 - 4/19/95. Seniority, premium pay, termination of employment, fringe benefits, reinstatement.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  5/2/94. Seniority, assignment of jobs. Employees submission to PLB #4948 with exhibits.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  5/2/94. Elimination of jobs. Employees submission to PLB #4948 with exhibits.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Suspension, compensation, elimination of jobs, seniority.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Promotion, testing. Exhibits.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  6/7/93. Reinstatement, seniority, compensation, termination of employment.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  12/20/94. Compensation.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  5/24/95. Reinstatement, compensation, discipline.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  5/24/95. Suspension, discipline, compensation.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  5/24/95. Call-in, compensation, back pay.
- St. Louis Southwestern Railway Co., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  5/24/95. Discipline, back pay, reinstatement, suspension.
- TNT Red Star Express, Inc., 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  10/10/91 -5/7/92. Termination of employment, dishonesty.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  2/87 - 9/14/87. Discipline, back pay, medical release/physical exam.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  9/20/94. Transcript of proceedings - medical release/ physical exam.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  3/8/93. Reinstatement, seniority, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  9/77. Reinstatement, seniority, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  3/30/93. Medical release/physical exam, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  3/30/93. reinstatement, seniority, back pay, medical release/physical exam.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  8/6/92 - 3/20/93. Termination of employment, back pay, suspension.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  3/30/93. Suspension, back pay, reinstatement.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  7/22/91 - 3/23/95. Reinstatement, seniority, back pay, suspension, medical release/physical exam, discipline.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  3/25/94 - 3/3/95. Reinstatement, back pay, discipline, suspension.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  7/25/91 -3/23/95. Seniority, promotions, compensation.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  9/14/88-11/27/88. Bidding, merger/acquisitions/sales of business.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  7/10/93 - 4/4/94. Discipline, back pay, suspension, seniority.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  5/24/94. Suspension, compensation, reinstatement, back pay, seniority.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  5/24/94. Reinstatement, back pay, seniority.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  5/24/94. Discipline, compensation.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  5/24/94. Suspension, compensation.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  2/17/94. Reinstatement, seniority, crew size.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Discipline, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  6/10/93. Crew size. **exhibits and transcripts of case follow the folder.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  8/25/94. Reinstatement, back pay, seniority.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  5/24/94 -10/25/94. Discipline, compensation, reinstatement, seniority, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  7/29/94. Reinstatement, seniority, back pay. Transcript of this case follows folder.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  2/24/92 -7/29/94. Reinstatement, seniority, back pay, discipline, compensation, suspension.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1987-1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  2/3/87 -10/25/94. Assignment of jobs, discipline, rates of pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  1/14/92 -5/28/93. Suspension, compensation, reinstatement, seniority, medical release/ physical exams, fringe benefits.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  5/31/88 - 7/9/90. Termination of employment, back pay, compensation, discipline, reinstatement, alcoholism/drug abuse.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  8/17/91 -9/30/91. Suspension, compensation, seniority, discipline, reinstatement, back pay.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  2/18/94 - 3/9/94. Reinstatement, compensation, discipline, suspension.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  3/28/95. Suspension, compensation.
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  3/28/94 -3/23/95. Assignment of jobs, rates of pay,
- Union Pacific Railroad Co., 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  1993 policy directives concerning Equal Employment Opportunity and other employment practices.
- United States Court of Appeals. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  List of appeal cases.
- United States Naval Academy, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  8/16/89 -10/10/89. Suspension, contract interpretation, termination of employment. Transcript follows folder.
- U.S. Patent Office, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  9/28/93 - 2/6/94. Evaluation.
- U.S. Air, 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  9/12/88-10/5/93. Suspension, termination of employment.
- Van Den Bergh Foods Co., 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  2/25/93 - 2/1/94. Termination of employment.
- Virginia Electric & Power Co., 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  11/5/92 -3/5/93. Alcoholism/drug abuse.
- Washington Gas & Light Co., 1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  6/19/92. Just correspondence about a case.
- Appendix to Hartman's statement. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  See Box #2, FF#11.
- Book: The Crew Size Dispute in the Railroad Industry. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Agreements from different companies.
- Folder with various pamphlets, correspondence and transcripts. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Just miscellaneous stuff. (Box 9, Folder 4)